

Eduardo Sancho Solano

GRADUATE IN MECHATRONICS ENGINEERING

I'm an ambititous team player with wide experience in industrial manufacturing,

Technological and organizational challenges that will have a significant impact on people's lives are what drive me and keep me motivated.

I feel more comfortable in a dynamic work environment where problem solving is frequently exercised and interpersonal communication is the key to reaching sustainable solutions.

PERSONAL INFO

EMAIL PHONE ADDRESS

edsancho18@yahoo.es +506 87101871 House 17, Barrio Nacaome. Cañas, Guanacaste, Costa Rica.

WORK HISTORY

Project Manager and Engineering Designer

2019-03 - present

Giro Industrial, San Carlos, Alajuela

Giro Industrial is a family owned company which manufactures machinery for the agro-industry such as mills, conveyors, fryers, etc.

- -Coordinated the definition of the Terms of Reference for New Products. This process involved the sales team, several clients, manufacturing managers and the board of directors.
- -Developed a **primary concept of the end product**, following the Terms of Reference. The concepts served as a guide to the manufacturing team to build the machines and helped to formulate a "shopping list" of the raw materials.
- -As the project progressed, sometimes more specific mechanical and electrical schematics were required. Either I made them myself or I asked a coworker to help me out. These were made in **Autodesk Inventor** and **AutoCAD**.
- -Programming of automation components such as VFDs (Yaskawa, Siemens), PLCs (Schneider, Fatek, Siemens), HMIs (Autonics, Maple). Programs were written in Ladder Logic or Function Block Diagram.

Fixture Designer (Intern)

2018-10 - 2018-12

Boston Scientific, Coyol, Alajuela

Boston Scientific has 3000+ employees working at their facilities in Coyol Alajuela, they manufacture medical devices mainly for endoscopy, urology and cardiology.

- -Because it was such a big company, I was required to deeply understand and practice their core values; which meant focusing on quality, organizational culture, and follow strictly regulated procedures.
- •Engineered and tested two fixture designs for two separate production units (fixtures are manual tools that workers use for specific tasks). The fixtures aimed to minimize cutting risks for workers, boost productivity and deliver more consistent batches of finished product.

Administrative Assistant and Product Design (Intern)

2019-07 - 2020-03

Fabrica Mi Pieza, Tilarán, Guanacaste

It was a Tech Start Up.

I did field support, on-site manufacturing, and lead management for some potential clients.

Maintenance Intern

2018-04 - 2018-06

Pelón de la Bajura, Liberia, Guanacaste

This company is the biggest rice and beans producer of Costa Rica.

- -Gathered technical and productive data of processes and machinery in order to later summarize it and then make it available for all technicians.
- -Assisted in the servicing of machines that failed unexpectedly and in programmed maintenance with outsourced technicians.

Mechatronics Intern

Top Tier, Portland, Oregon

This company build palletizing machines.

Assisted the manufacturing process, always supervised and mentored by someone.

- -Assembly of control panels.
- -Set-up of CNC Lathe.
- -Operating a brake press for sheet metal.
- -Testing and troubleshooting of assemblied machines on-site.

EDUCATION

Universidad Invenio, Cañas, Guanacaste, Costa Rica

Licenciatura, Ingeniería Mecatrónica

2017-10 - 2017-12

SKILLS

 Autodesk Inventor **** **** Democratic Leadership **** Problem Solving

SOFTWARE

Microsoft Office

LANGUAGES

**** Spanish **** ■ German **** Italian

HOBBY

- ·Home automation using Arduino.
- -Playing and designing simple videogames.
- -Travelling and interacting closely with other cultures.

PROJECTS

Solar Panel Cleaner

2021-01 - 2021-06

Project Owner

Lightweight/Portable cleaning module equipped with medium hardness circular brushes driven by 12Vdc electric motors that could be operated using a tractor's battery as power source.

REFERENCES

Gilbert Rojas

Founder and Director, Giro Industrial

2017-01 - 2020-12